hello AI Wave riders welcome
in another day of how we can utilize AI
to build any customized application for our needs
today I'm going to show you something great which I built um
within days using the current AI technologies
it takes any video like let's say from Instagram or YouTube
it downloads it inside of your local computer and then if we want
we can transcribe the video
meaning
I will take everything which have been spoken inside of this video
using Whisper AI
locally as well so far everything is for free
and then I will save all of these text inside of a Google sheet
as well into the database
this is gonna be utilized later if we want to change the text
if we want like to make a new transcript for our next video and so on
and the third layer is like we spoke before
I can upload this video automatically
the video which I have edited for myself
like a finished one
where I use this transcript which I downloaded and the video etcetera
then I can upload them automatically to to the to Google Drive
okay so let's see the application of how it works
right now I will go to Instagram for example
and let me close this and let's us choose this one
it has a completely different thumbnail
it's a video where I actually speak about uh specific content
I'm gonna come here copy the link and I will
go back to the application and then I will paste it
we have like three layers like we talked before we have the download
transcribe and upload so we start here and then we click on add URL
it adds this to a text file called urls dot text
and then we click on the checkbox here to start downloading it
because we can download multiple videos at once
so right now I'm gonna try only with one video
then we can click here on side of start download
it will start downloading like you can see here
then we click on start downloading and it starts downloading
like you can see here
and you see it also what happens in the background
where it's saving it the name of the video etcetera
after we have finished downloading it
we can go and check what's going on inside of our um folder
which is extremely interesting
and when we go to the folder
I can show you here what's going on
uh we go to the thumbnails first of all
we will notice it downloading the thumbnail separately
so we can utilize it if we want
like there is a different system which I built
I will talk about it in another video
where we can build also thumbnails
uh automatically then we have the video which have been downloaded
this is the video and the second one and if we click on it
so this is the video which have been downloaded
like you can see awesome
we have the video and we go back to our folder and if we click on uh
we still go back to assets downloads
we notice also the transcript which we have talked about still
we didn't utilize that
but we see the file have been updated and if we open this file
we will notice the following
you will see here we have almost everything um
like before I already downloaded this file
but here you will see also the second file
it have been downloaded we have the video name
we have the date of the downloading
and then here we have different columns
talking if we uploaded this video already or not
this is used later in another N8N workflow
which I can show you of how we can utilize it to post our own video
and like you can see here you have everything
um literally from did we post it on Instagram
did we create the thumbnail and so on and then the transcript
this is a very important column
because you will see right now
how I can transcribe the video completely
let me minimize this for now and go back to my flow
and in the flow we notice here also we have the transcript
I have two videos so far I didn't transcribe any one of them
I can choose both of them
being like to get transcribed at the same time
and like
I told you we will download this transcripts not only to Google Sheet
also to our database so we can utilize it at any time
I'm gonna click on start transcription
this is a very heavy process
so it might take a bit of time and in the meanwhile
I can go back to the second terminal
I'm gonna showing show you what's going on
you will notice here they are being like transcribed 31%
63% it's using like the local Whisper AI
which I have downloaded into my machine
so it finished from the first video
I can go back to the main screen so it's it's here
so it's processing still not done sorry for that um
but you can see it's right now at 45% and it's still going here
like you can see
there is also the possibility right now I am not connecting it
but there is a way also
it's already implemented where I can change the transcript using uh
open AI so right now you see both of them have been updated
and let's go to the screen to see what's going on
one thing you will notice the file didn't get updated
the reason why it didn't get updated is because during transcription
I had it open and when it's open
it can unfortunately not override the file
so I had to close it
but the good part like I mentioned at the beginning
if this fails um
it does it actually in the database
so I can get still the transcription from the database
but to ensure that this does never fails
we always need to close the file
um let me open open it here
and then let's go to the social media DB
OK once we open our database
we will notice we have this video transcripts table
and inside of it we have everything like from the video
you will notice we have the description of the video
not just the transcription
so inside of the video we get this Google tool just blew my mind
instantly edit image with just a prompt
I'm gonna show you where it is exactly inside of the video
so if we go back to our main screen and then we click on here
we will notice this Google tool just blew my mind instantly
it even took the description from here
and going back to the database
we will also notice other things like for example okay
who's what username is it
what kind of platform did we fetch it from
uh the duration of the video is 68 seconds and we have also the ratio
the width and the height uh
and we have almost every data that we might need in the future
we get the thumbnail and we get the video
and the most important one is the transcription
which I just mentioned a moment ago
you will see here we have everything what I speak inside of the video
it starts with this is Google uh
nano banana like it's not completely correct
but this is Google Nano Banana
confirmed the new state of the art image editor
that lets you transfer visuals with nothing
so if we go to back to the video and then we start it again
you will see this is Google Nano Banana
and new state of the art editor
and it's exactly what we can see here
because we had the problem that the cheat was closed
but it should normally update the cheat and not just update the cheat
it should also download it upload it to Google Drive
so we go to our transcription here
and then we paste it and then we should have it something like this
I'm gonna close this for now and then I'm gonna go back to the flow
and here we are going to talk about the third layer
the third layer like I told you it's going to upload into the drive
the most interesting part it's not gonna only upload to Google Drive
I built my own AI Wave Rider Drive Manager
this was only possible with the use of AI
like it speeded up the process like crazy
we literally live in a crazy time
but I'm gonna show you also how it gets uploaded there
so if we click on thumbnails we have the thumbnails
the one I uploaded before I created the video
and this is the one we just
created right now so if we click on upload
selected thumbnail and then we go back to our terminal
we will see it's getting being
it's like it getting uploaded and we have here successful status
uh to our AI wave rider and here is my inside of my file manager
if you see here I just click on refresh
here is the thumbnail this is extremely crazy
all of this inside of my ecosystem
and it was only possible because
I was able to speed up the development process using AI
if I click on the download
you will see the image have been downloaded here
and then we change into the other screen to see the image here
it is completely downloaded
like I can use it later to change it
for example for my own video based on the trans
uh the script that I have based on my brand
based on the hooks that I wanna use and it can change it completely
like for example for me
I always select change it to robots or change it to my own face
with adding these titles that you see in the screen
this is now the thumbnail
and you will notice also here below we have the sheets
uh and we have the DB updates
it's telling us what is going on and what is happening
and we also have the process status like for example
we downloaded we transcribed and we have uh the uploads
and we have the database updates
sheet updates
and you will notice here that AI Wave Rider is connected
the Google sheet is connected and the database is connected
and we have the last status which is the GPU
if you have a GPU inside of your computer
the process is gonna be sped up
like especially for the transcription part
since we are using Whisper AI models locally
this is gonna make it fast
if not it is going to work but it's gonna be a bit slower
so that is all uh for this video
I hope you enjoyed it
I hope that you are excited as I am of what is coming
and if you have any idea
if you have any application inside of your mind
and you want that we build it together in a video
which I will stream live let me know
write it down in the comments and we can do this together
and you will be astonished of how fast we can build these things
nowadays
stay updated stay connected and see you soon AI Wave riders
have a wonderful time and until then